[SPEAKER_01]: This, uh, where'd you, where'd you, did you grow up around this area?
[SPEAKER_01]: I was born in Ohio.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, whereabouts in Ohio?
[SPEAKER_01]: Rent a little town down.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm from Ohio.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'm from Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_03]: Cleveland, well, I'm, I'm right down on the Indiana line, almost.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_01]: The dark county, the part of the... That's Greenville around there?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yep.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you, uh, live there very long?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well,
[SPEAKER_03]: I was there until I was 18 and I went east to college.
[SPEAKER_03]: Where did you go to school?
[SPEAKER_03]: I went to Juniata College and graduated there and then went to Springfield College up in Springfield, Massachusetts.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did you happen to go to Springfield from Juniata?
[SPEAKER_01]: Athletic.
[SPEAKER_03]: Athletic College.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's where basketball was invented, baseball.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you play basketball?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you know Nate Smith?
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, hell no, he was a... Basketball was invented in 1891, I was born in 1892.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he wasn't still there then though, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you play basketball and baseball in Springfield?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yep.
[SPEAKER_01]: I did track work.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you graduate from Springfield?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yep.
[SPEAKER_01]: What'd you do then?
[SPEAKER_01]: Then I went into baseball.
[SPEAKER_03]: When I graduated, I was due to go to St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_01]: What did you graduate then?
[SPEAKER_01]: What year would you have graduated?
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you remember?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, 16.
[SPEAKER_01]: 1916?
[SPEAKER_01]: I see.
[SPEAKER_01]: And you're due to go to St. Louis?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: How would that work out?
[SPEAKER_01]: Who signed you?
[SPEAKER_03]: It's kind of a funny story.
[SPEAKER_03]: I, uh, when I was in Juliana College in Huntington, Pennsylvania, I played on a summer semi-pro team, you know.
[SPEAKER_03]: And we were a planet team from Atlantic City.
[SPEAKER_03]: It was managed by Earl Mack, that's Cardi Mack's son.
[SPEAKER_03]: And, uh,
[SPEAKER_03]: They were there three days.
[SPEAKER_03]: And when I got back, when they left, a few days later I got a letter from Connie Mack to come down and join his club.
[SPEAKER_03]: By the way, I was a catcher then.
[SPEAKER_03]: So I did.
[SPEAKER_03]: I went down to Mack's.
[SPEAKER_03]: I stayed around there.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh,
[SPEAKER_03]: till almost September.
[SPEAKER_03]: That was in August.
[SPEAKER_03]: And old Bert Conner, an old-time ball player, was managing a club in the Ohio Pennsylvania League.
[SPEAKER_03]: And they were at Chester, Pennsylvania at the time, and he came up there, and he had no Chester, and Mac gave him me.
[SPEAKER_03]: Finished the season.
[SPEAKER_03]: So I went down there and finished the season, and then after the American League season was over, well I just, naturally went back to school.
[SPEAKER_03]: So I, he sent, he sent me up to Utica the next year under Mike O'Neill, one of the famous old O'Neill batters, he was the pitcher.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I caught one game and played third base the rest of the time.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was it the New York State League?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I wasn't a catcher so Mack didn't exercise his option on me.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was drafted by St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_01]: How'd they know about you, you know?
[SPEAKER_03]: Who?
[SPEAKER_01]: St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did they have somebody scouting up there?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did anybody come and see you particularly?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, the scout that was up there was Pauline Kelchner.
[SPEAKER_03]: And he had his club draft name.
[SPEAKER_03]: So I went to St. Louis and
[SPEAKER_03]: following spring.
[SPEAKER_03]: 1917.
[SPEAKER_03]: By the way, the manager of that, not the manager, but the big shot, the business manager, was
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, the father that brought up the first nigger.
[SPEAKER_03]: Ricky.
[SPEAKER_03]: Frank Ricky, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Frank Ricky.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: He didn't stay with the club long.
[SPEAKER_03]: He went someplace else.
[SPEAKER_03]: And the manager of the club at that time was himself a field manager with Fielder Jones.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: The old White Sox.
[SPEAKER_01]: How was he to play under Fielder Jones?
[SPEAKER_01]: Fine.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Good manager, was he?
[SPEAKER_01]: He handled players pretty well?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was he still playing himself then?
[SPEAKER_03]: No.
[SPEAKER_03]: You see, that club was taken over, or took over, the old St. Louis Federal League Club at that time.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, that's right.
[SPEAKER_01]: Phil Ball was the owner, right?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, Phil Ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: He had the Federal League Club when they merged here.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's right, and Phil was there and
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, Bob Quinn was the business manager.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you know those people?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Phil Ball, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Was he a pretty nice chap?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, we didn't see much of him, though.
[SPEAKER_03]: I like Bob Quinn.
[SPEAKER_03]: His son has mixed up in baseball for years, John Quinn.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was the business manager, was he?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did he have much to do with the players?
[SPEAKER_01]: When you signed a contract, for example, did you sign to negotiate with him?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, who was on that team in 1917, the Browns?
[SPEAKER_01]: How about George Sisler?
[SPEAKER_03]: George Sisler was at first base.
[SPEAKER_03]: Darryl Pratt was at second base.
[SPEAKER_03]: Doc LaVanne was at the shortstop.
[SPEAKER_03]: And Pepper Austin was at the third base.
[SPEAKER_03]: And Jacobson was the center fielder.
[SPEAKER_03]: Norway had about six or seven top fielders, of course.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was that Elmer Miller?
[SPEAKER_01]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: What Miller was that?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, left hander.
[SPEAKER_03]: Right fielder.
[SPEAKER_03]: Elmer?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yep.
[SPEAKER_03]: And then there was Alan Sutherland was the pitcher, and Bob Groom, Ernie Coob.
[SPEAKER_03]: Coob?
[SPEAKER_03]: He pitched an 0-hitter that year?
[SPEAKER_03]: I was there.
[SPEAKER_03]: That was a year ago today.
[SPEAKER_03]: I mean, so many years ago today.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_01]: Tell me about that game, if you remember very well.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, you see, there were two no-hit games pitched by the same club in two days.
[SPEAKER_03]: But it happened to be one of those games was a doubleheader.
[SPEAKER_03]: Bob Bloom pitched one, and Ernie Kuhl pitched the other.
[SPEAKER_03]: One day, it was at the old Chicago West Side.
[SPEAKER_03]: Like in the same club that was the Black Sox.
[SPEAKER_03]: Jackson and... of course he wasn't a Black Sox neither was Eddie Collins.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, you were in those games?
[SPEAKER_01]: Those no-hitters?
[SPEAKER_01]: You played them?
[SPEAKER_01]: One.
[SPEAKER_01]: What was your position then?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, I was utility infielder then, they called me.
[SPEAKER_03]: Which game did you play, in Coober or Groom?
[SPEAKER_03]: I played in...
[SPEAKER_03]: in the first game, that was cool.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was quite a thrill, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_01]: Were you aware that this was developing into a no-hitter as the game went on?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I didn't start that game.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was a finish runner.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, you don't start to think of those things after about five or six innings.
[SPEAKER_01]: You played infield then after you went in the game?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, I was just, I went in as a pinch runner for the pitcher.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I played another pitcher.
[SPEAKER_03]: For a relief pitcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: Anything like a base hit in that game?
[SPEAKER_01]: Hm?
[SPEAKER_01]: Any tough chances in that game?
[SPEAKER_01]: I mean, it might have been base hits or...
[SPEAKER_01]: great feeling?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, I don't think it was, I don't think, I think it was just, that's just a routine game with a hundred and thirty hits, that was all that wasn't anything sensational about it.
[SPEAKER_01]: But if you went in for the pitcher, how could it be a complete game?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, no, I'm, you know, I'm, I'm, I'm all wet about that.
[SPEAKER_03]: I played in the, in the second game of that doubleheader.
[SPEAKER_03]: I see.
[SPEAKER_03]: I mean, I played the same day.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I went in to run for eighty-five, by the way.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yes?
[SPEAKER_03]: And so I wasn't in the no-hitter.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was in the second game of that doubleheader.
[SPEAKER_01]: The no-hitter was the first game of the doubleheader?
[SPEAKER_01]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: The no-hitter was in the first game of the doubleheader?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: And you were in the second.
[SPEAKER_03]: And the second game of the doubleheader spoiled the consecutive no-hit games.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Coog pitched his, the, was that the first game that Coog pitched and Groom the day before?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, Groom.
[SPEAKER_01]: Pitched the first game that day and Coog the day before.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's amazing, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_01]: Two consecutive no-hitters there.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, they weren't consecutive.
[SPEAKER_03]: The second game was a double-hitter.
[SPEAKER_03]: That wasn't a no-hitter.
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_03]: See, the first game of the double-hitter was no-hitter.
[SPEAKER_03]: Then the second game wasn't a no-hitter.
[SPEAKER_03]: The next day.
[SPEAKER_03]: The next day, the game was pitched by Bob Groom.
[SPEAKER_03]: I see.
[SPEAKER_01]: That is pretty remarkable.
[SPEAKER_01]: Two out of three.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, what was your biggest thrill in baseball?
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you have any things that stand out in your mind?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, nothing particular.
[SPEAKER_01]: What's George Sister like?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, he was a swell fellow.
[SPEAKER_01]: Very nice chap.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about Baby Doll?
[SPEAKER_03]: Good hitter.
[SPEAKER_03]: Good fielder for a big fella.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a great big fella.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, he was a good fella.
[SPEAKER_03]: And a good ball player, too.
[SPEAKER_03]: Gotta be a pretty good fielder for a standard fielder, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: And, uh... Did, uh... Ricky manage all the while you were with the Browns?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: He left.
[SPEAKER_03]: He went to...
[SPEAKER_01]: Cardinals, did he?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did he jump to the Cardinals?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yes, he did, in fact.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yep, he did.
[SPEAKER_03]: He went to the Cardinals.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did Branch Rickey treat you?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, he didn't get to see much of it.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was manager there, and he wasn't there very long after the season started.
[SPEAKER_01]: How long did you stay with the Browns?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well I just, see that was the year the war broke out.
[SPEAKER_03]: I see, uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_03]: And everybody was being drafted and so on and so forth.
[SPEAKER_03]: So, I was standing on the corner one night after a game in front of the Beers Hotel.
[SPEAKER_03]: And there was an army camp outside St. Louis, I can't remember what it was now.
[SPEAKER_01]: Jefferson Barracks?
[SPEAKER_01]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_03]: Jefferson Barracks?
[SPEAKER_03]: I can't remember.
[SPEAKER_03]: But anyway, I was sitting out there and the Elkos every night, they have parades, you know, all over, you know.
[SPEAKER_03]: And here come a big old truck full of soldiers and so on and so forth.
[SPEAKER_03]: I stand there on the curb, looking up, and one monkey look at me and he say, bud, what's the matter with you?
[SPEAKER_03]: They got in my skin.
[SPEAKER_01]: You went in there?
[SPEAKER_01]: Mm-hmm.
[SPEAKER_01]: They were in the Marines.
[SPEAKER_01]: How long were you in the Marines?
[SPEAKER_01]: Eight years.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you play any more baseball?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, yes and no.
[SPEAKER_03]: I...
[SPEAKER_03]: When I came back, I didn't...
[SPEAKER_03]: I resigned my commission in the Marines.
[SPEAKER_03]: My wife insisted I do that because I was never home.
[SPEAKER_03]: You were an officer in the Marines?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, I was a captain.
[SPEAKER_03]: And then I came back home and Springfield College recommended me as a coach up at Worcester Polytechnic Institute in Worcester, Massachusetts.
[SPEAKER_03]: So I went up there.
[SPEAKER_03]: my baseball team part of, you know, been out for eight years.
[SPEAKER_03]: But down below though, Worcester was down in East Chagos with a fellow that was a baseball nut and a millionaire.
[SPEAKER_03]: So he had a baseball team.
[SPEAKER_03]: He sat up and wondered if I'd come down and play.
[SPEAKER_03]: So I did.
[SPEAKER_03]: Went down and played.
[SPEAKER_03]: We had quite a good ball club.
[SPEAKER_03]: Bump Hadley was a pitcher.
[SPEAKER_03]: Hank Greenberg was first baseman.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's when he was a high school boy.
[SPEAKER_03]: And... Gene doesn't tell the old catcher.
[SPEAKER_03]: We had a good ball club.
[SPEAKER_01]: Where'd you live after you got out of the Marines?
[SPEAKER_01]: Worcester, Massachusetts.
[SPEAKER_01]: And when'd you come here?
[SPEAKER_01]: I came here in 58.
[SPEAKER_03]: How'd you happen to move here?
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, my father had this property up there, and he died, and I inherited it, and so I like fishing.
[SPEAKER_03]: Got a lot of lakes around here, and I come up here.
[SPEAKER_01]: You do a lot of fishing, do you?
[SPEAKER_01]: Mm-hmm.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you do hunting during the off-season when you were playing ball?
[SPEAKER_01]: A lot of ball players went hunting, didn't they?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Where did you go hunting?
[SPEAKER_01]: Up in Michigan here, or up in Maine, or wherever you went?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, when I was in Massachusetts, I went to Maine, New Hampshire, and did some deer hunting, and I did small game hunting in Massachusetts, and I hunted some deer in Massachusetts.
[SPEAKER_03]: Since I came here, this is one of the best hunting states in
[SPEAKER_03]: In the Union, it's a lot of deer since then.
[SPEAKER_03]: I think it was 97,000 deer killed in the last season.
[SPEAKER_03]: It's a lot of deer.
[SPEAKER_01]: When did you get married?
[SPEAKER_03]: I think it was...
[SPEAKER_03]: 1922.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, after you were in the service then, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: But you didn't play any more professional baseball after you went in the Marines?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't know regular.
[SPEAKER_01]: So your professional, you played just with Utica?
[SPEAKER_01]: Gettysburg.
[SPEAKER_01]: Gettysburg?
[SPEAKER_01]: When was that?
[SPEAKER_01]: Was that before?
[SPEAKER_01]: Utica?
[SPEAKER_03]: Before Utica, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Teddy Flankel.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he coached there, didn't he?
[SPEAKER_01]: The college there, after a while.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, his brother.
[SPEAKER_01]: Right.
[SPEAKER_03]: Ira, his brother.
[SPEAKER_03]: His brother managed the club that I played on.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you know him pretty well?
[SPEAKER_01]: Go ahead and vote.
[SPEAKER_01]: Uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_01]: He booked it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Great pitcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: What did you study at college?
[SPEAKER_01]: Anything particular?
[SPEAKER_01]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: What studies did you major in college?
[SPEAKER_01]: Anything in particular?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, in Juneau, it was an A.B.
[SPEAKER_03]: A.B.
[SPEAKER_03]: course?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, just regular arts course.
[SPEAKER_01]: Uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you go four years there?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then you went to Springfield for more?
[SPEAKER_01]: Mm-hmm.
[SPEAKER_01]: What degree did you get at Springfield?
[SPEAKER_01]: You get a physical education, P, National Physical Education.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you coach at Worcester after you went up there?
[SPEAKER_01]: You coached their baseball team there?
[SPEAKER_03]: Coached baseball, basketball, football.
[SPEAKER_01]: How long did you do that?
[SPEAKER_01]: 22 years.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_01]: That would be from about when now, 1920?
[SPEAKER_01]: 1921.
[SPEAKER_03]: Took 41.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_01]: 43.
[SPEAKER_01]: You coached all those years, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yep.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you have any championship teams?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I had an undefeated team.
[SPEAKER_03]: First one, the only one they ever had.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's football.
[SPEAKER_03]: We had a good basketball team.
[SPEAKER_03]: We won the Wiener Championship several times.
[SPEAKER_01]: Any of your players go on to professional sports at all?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, they were all engineer graduates.
[SPEAKER_03]: Actually, they weren't interested in anything but getting out and getting a job.
[SPEAKER_01]: You were eight years in the Marines.
[SPEAKER_01]: You were overseas for a couple of years.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then you were in France, were you?
[SPEAKER_03]: Mm-hmm.
[SPEAKER_01]: And when you came back here, where were you stationed?
[SPEAKER_03]: When I got back here, I went to San Domingo.
[SPEAKER_01]: One of the occupations down there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yep.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, any interesting stories that happened in your baseball career?
[SPEAKER_01]: Funny incidents?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: Anything stand out?
[SPEAKER_03]: I never really had a chance, as far as baseball was concerned.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was still pretty young when I went in the service, and I didn't stay up there long.
[SPEAKER_03]: I jumped in the Marines and never went back.
[SPEAKER_03]: Just sort of like half-hearted thing.
[SPEAKER_03]: Didn't know anything.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about your year at Utica?
[SPEAKER_01]: How'd you do there?
[SPEAKER_01]: What'd you hit, do you remember?
[SPEAKER_01]: batting average?
[SPEAKER_01]: Two-eight is right.
[SPEAKER_01]: Uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did they play a pretty long schedule?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, pretty long.
[SPEAKER_01]: Any players in that league that made it big later?
[SPEAKER_01]: Remember?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, George Burns.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is that the George Burns who played the Indians or the one with the Giants?
[SPEAKER_01]: Giants.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, there's quite a few of them.
[SPEAKER_01]: I can't remember them all.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's a pretty good league, I guess.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, Jack Leary, he went catching for Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was your manager up there again?
[SPEAKER_03]: Up there was the same as ever, Mike O'Neill.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's Steve O'Neill family?
[SPEAKER_03]: A brother.
[SPEAKER_03]: And then the old catcher, O'Neill, you see, that was the thing that sold O'Neill batteries.
[SPEAKER_01]: Steve O'Neal.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you ever meet any old ballplayers anymore?
[SPEAKER_01]: See any?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_03]: I could see them if I'd go to their reunions and so forth, but I don't have that kind of position to go, Harvey.
[SPEAKER_03]: Who asked me if I knew this Collemore?
[SPEAKER_03]: Wasn't he a pitcher?
[SPEAKER_01]: Who's that?
[SPEAKER_01]: Collemore.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: I called him up this morning.
[SPEAKER_01]: He didn't want to talk to me.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's up at Battle Creek there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Alan Collemore.
[SPEAKER_01]: I thought it was Harry, but it's Alan.
[SPEAKER_01]: He had a short career, about 1912 or 13, I think.
[SPEAKER_01]: Forgotten who it was.
[SPEAKER_01]: A fellow named Tooley over at Marshall.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, he?
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: He had a short career too.
[SPEAKER_01]: Have any old baseball books or records or anything?
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, I got a lot.
[SPEAKER_01]: Any old, any pictures you have of yourself in baseball uniform?
[SPEAKER_03]: I got one right over here now.
[SPEAKER_01]: You like to watch baseball on television?
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh yes, I sure follow it.
[SPEAKER_01]: You haven't lost interest in it, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Nope.
[SPEAKER_01]: You ever get the sporting news at all?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'll talk into the recorder here, just so I can.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's given me here a 1974 membership card to the Old Time Ball Players Association of Wisconsin.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the board of advisors have quite a list of names here.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_01]: Some great ones here, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yep.
[SPEAKER_01]: Very nice.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do they have regular meetings or annual meetings, maybe?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, every year they have one.
[SPEAKER_03]: They get to take some of the football game in the Chicago or someplace like that, and they all tend to have a meeting there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Have you been able to get to any of these?
[SPEAKER_03]: I never have gone up.
[SPEAKER_01]: Art Mansfield, I never heard of him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Diney Mansfield.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, there's a lot of them.
[SPEAKER_03]: You probably haven't heard of them.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Don't hammer it like me.
[SPEAKER_01]: You got a scrapbook there, have you?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, I got one here.
[SPEAKER_03]: Uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's handled.
[SPEAKER_01]: These are some nice little pictures, aren't they?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is when you were at college, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was that Gettysburg club.
[SPEAKER_01]: Eddie Plank, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: And there's his brother, I think, in America.
[SPEAKER_03]: And there's me.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't have any old pictures you could spare.
[SPEAKER_01]: I haven't got any.
[SPEAKER_01]: What's this?
[SPEAKER_01]: That was a Junior.
[SPEAKER_03]: Do you have any of these pictures here?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: This is the Juniata.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's the Juniata, that's the Springview.
[SPEAKER_03]: There's Leslie Maddow.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you know him pretty well?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, he was on the Springview with me.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was that right?
[SPEAKER_01]: He's the one that, remember Douglas?
[SPEAKER_01]: Bill Douglas, right?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, yeah, he turned Bill in.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, I guess he had to.
[SPEAKER_03]: Is he still living?
[SPEAKER_03]: As far as I know, he'd be about my age.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did he call you Pete?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: He left me in there.
[SPEAKER_03]: I had a fellow man here who hanged Greenberg and I can't find the book.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, is that right?
[SPEAKER_01]: He had a couple of scrapbooks here of his college days and early professional days, which I've just been glancing through.
[SPEAKER_03]: This is when I retired.
[SPEAKER_03]: After I got through coaching, I had a job
[SPEAKER_03]: factory there, a production supervisor.
[SPEAKER_03]: Howard and Schuster?
[SPEAKER_02]: Schuster.
[SPEAKER_02]: Can I take a look at the picture there?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, here it is.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_01]: Here's the
[SPEAKER_01]: Telegram dated...
[SPEAKER_01]: I can't spot a date on this.
[SPEAKER_01]: When would this have been?
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you remember?
[SPEAKER_03]: That was the year that I retired from...
[SPEAKER_03]: Coaching?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, from...
[SPEAKER_03]: I was supervisor of production in this factory there.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's what... Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_03]: That was...
[SPEAKER_01]: In the 50s then?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, 58.
[SPEAKER_01]: This was in North Grafton, Massachusetts?
[SPEAKER_01]: Or where was it?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, this was in Worcester, Massachusetts.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is a telegram from Hank Greenberg at the time of his retirement.
[SPEAKER_01]: It says, when Schuster has conveyed to me your kind invitation to be with you for the Pete Bigler dinner and testimonial, nothing would please me more than to be with Pete and all his friends for this occasion as I remember fondly our baseball days together.
[SPEAKER_01]: After he was in high school, due to previous engagements, I'm not able to accept your convocation.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, here's a way out of it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you ever want to extend my warm congratulations and best wishes to Pete and all his friends?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, isn't that nice?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, we had this bunkhead, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: He died not too awful long ago.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you have this picture in the wall there?
[SPEAKER_01]: That's you, is it not?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: No, that was put in that book and given to me afterwards, after the banquet.
[SPEAKER_01]: That picture behind here, though, the one in the frame?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: You don't have that?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, I got that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, did you?
[SPEAKER_03]: It's a great big thing, though.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: These are all pictures from that.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, that's all pictures of the banquet.
[SPEAKER_01]: What was your playing weight?
[SPEAKER_03]: 150.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you ever have trouble getting into shape in the spring?
[SPEAKER_03]: No.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was playing basketball all winter.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, you kept in shape as a coach, I'll bet.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, yes.
[SPEAKER_01]: Very interesting.
[SPEAKER_01]: Very nice.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, it's been very nice talking to you.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, nice to talk to you.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, we'll probably run into patches of fog while we're here.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because we have at night.
[SPEAKER_01]: Okay, we're about 10.30 on Wednesday night, July 24, 1974, driving back from Bluefield, West Virginia to our motel in Beckley.
[SPEAKER_01]: We've just interviewed Fred Sheriff Blake, who lives at
[SPEAKER_00]: 106 Lewis Street, Bloomfield.
[SPEAKER_01]: Whose telephone number is?
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Neither do I.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's on the other sheet.
[SPEAKER_01]: We had a real good interview.
[SPEAKER_01]: We got there, we called him up from Beckley.
[SPEAKER_01]: I got his, I had his address in
[SPEAKER_01]: Beckley but turned out it was wrong.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was a parking lot.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, it was a vacant lot and we walked into the Sheriff's office in Beckley and he knew Sheriff Blake, who never was a sheriff by the way, but we got his We got the street in which he lived in Bluefield
[SPEAKER_01]: Went back to our motel, called up Bluefield Information, got his phone number, then called him up and got him.
[SPEAKER_01]: So he was willing to see us at 7 o'clock.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was all about 4 o'clock in the afternoon, so we set it for 7.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then came on down here and had supper and so on, got out to his house about 7 o'clock, and had a real good interview.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, there are a couple of things which didn't come on the tape.
[SPEAKER_01]: that we thought we ought to talk about so driving back here to keep us occupied as we go through patches of fog on this rather overcast but comfortable evening we thought we'd fill up the rest of this Ivan Bigler one half of tape with some of our thoughts and some of the other things so go ahead
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, the mine that he worked for, and I guess his father must have worked for it too, was the Staniford, S-T-A-N-A-F-O-R-D, number two mine of the New River Coal Company.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did you find that out?
[SPEAKER_00]: there was a picture of them putting in some fancy equipment in the late 1950s and his picture was in the paper with two other men as having dreamt up this fancy equipment or something whatever it was.
[SPEAKER_00]: Apparently he worked with the electrical part of the mine because he strung those high tension wires
[SPEAKER_00]: in the mountains and i would say he was working on until the 1950s yeah well 74 and say 54 he'd have been 56 or 55 so i mean it's very possible he said he worked about 20 years after baseball about 10 years before which would be about right yeah
[SPEAKER_00]: going into the mines as a kid yeah he started working in the mines by 1941-42 and he worked till 62 he'd have gotten 20 years in of course he managed Huntington in 41 that was the first time he'd ever been kicked out of a baseball game in all the years because there's a picture in one of the clippings of that was that right yeah i'm saying they finally got him
[SPEAKER_01]: He had two huge scrapbooks.
[SPEAKER_01]: The one I looked at, the material was all loose.
[SPEAKER_01]: There were a few pages, a lot of pages with pasted stuff, but a lot of loose stuff too.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the pages had broken free from their loosely binding.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know, was your scrapbook in the same shape?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, they all needed reinforcements.
[SPEAKER_01]: Needed to be remounted, redone.
[SPEAKER_02]: Okay, uh, describe him.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, my.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, he's tall, trim, good-looking, with a nice shock of white hair, very neat in his habits.
[SPEAKER_00]: His apartment was neat.
[SPEAKER_00]: All his suits were very carefully hung up.
[SPEAKER_00]: His shoes were polished.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was kind of a dirty looking place from the outside, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, but it was... And it wasn't that ornate inside, but it was... Well, I imagine that'll be furniture.
[SPEAKER_00]: That'll be furnished.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, he probably rents it furnished.
[SPEAKER_00]: I imagine he's gotten rid of everything.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because I think he never really has gotten over his wife's death.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the program where he had put flowers in the church was dated May, would I tell you?
[SPEAKER_02]: 1965?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, it was May 23rd or something, 1965.
[SPEAKER_00]: So she must have died about that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: And now I can't stand being in the one place very long.
[SPEAKER_00]: She likes to pack up and go.
[SPEAKER_00]: When the spirit moves her.
[SPEAKER_01]: Teddy never drove much.
[SPEAKER_01]: She did all the driving, I guess.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he was in the big time.
[SPEAKER_01]: Even now he doesn't have a car.
[SPEAKER_01]: He goes like he's going to go to Beckley tomorrow.
[SPEAKER_01]: We thought we might interview him in Beckley tomorrow morning.
[SPEAKER_01]: The sheriff was going to take me out to meet him, but we figured it'd be better to get him at home in the event he had pictures and things like he did.
[SPEAKER_01]: So we got him there, but he does drive up to Beckley from time to time.
[SPEAKER_01]: He goes by bus, though.
[SPEAKER_01]: He says he gets the bus just down the corner.
[SPEAKER_01]: He goes to many places by bus.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's just more convenient than
[SPEAKER_00]: my car you know what was i telling you that he was telling me when you were out in the car ladies day oh yeah about ladies day we have something on the tape about that but yeah okay so i read this article and it was talking about who was uh what was wrigley's name sam or william william okay well was there a spud wrigley son was philip i guess that may be
[SPEAKER_00]: all right so he went apparently he went into the regal stadium in california one day and he looked at the stands and he said yeah how horrible that was practically a quote because it was all men in the stands and this he disliked intensely the father did well i don't know which i take it was his son because he liked women and so but maybe it was the father i don't know
[SPEAKER_00]: and he said something has got to be done about this so he was letting the women in free three days a week and he thought that was much nicer and the other ball clubs started to complain so what they did was
[SPEAKER_00]: he may worked out the financial arrangements because he's had he couldn't stand seeing only men in the stands and he worked out an arrangement and paid the women actually i think it cost him something like 35 cents for every woman that came in free on these days that he had ladies day but he regularly paid it so the women would come to the ball games
[SPEAKER_00]: Which I thought was quite interesting.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was in one of those scrapbooks.
[SPEAKER_01]: We're now approaching the Princeton and the southern end of the turnpike which will be going on if I don't miss the exit here.
[SPEAKER_01]: What else did he tell you while I was outside?
[SPEAKER_01]: I went out to get cameras after the first hour.
[SPEAKER_01]: We got a good two-hour tape.
[SPEAKER_01]: Assuming it taped.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, there was something else I told you that he told me about while you were outside.
[SPEAKER_00]: Not that I read.
[SPEAKER_00]: That he told me.
And what was it?
[SPEAKER_01]: About his sister?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, no, I don't think that was it.
[SPEAKER_00]: But his younger sister.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had three sisters, apparently, and the youngest sister lives in Beckley.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he says she's his boss now.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she owns half the medical center with some doctor.
[SPEAKER_00]: She does.
[SPEAKER_00]: Better slow down.
[SPEAKER_00]: Approaching the...
[SPEAKER_01]: Entry to the turnpike.
[SPEAKER_01]: What about his wife and her influence?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I think that she must have done an awful lot for him now.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's just my opinion because He could tell she was a looker Morning yes.
[SPEAKER_01]: Good morning.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't get this good morning.
[SPEAKER_00]: I
[SPEAKER_00]: Unless our watches are wrong.
[SPEAKER_01]: I got quarter to eleven.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's a good morning.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's what I've got son.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'm wondering if we should have a cup of coffee.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is there a stock joint up here?
[SPEAKER_02]: I think there is.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well anyway, um, I mean, they made a very handsome couple.
[SPEAKER_00]: But you could just tell by the way she looked in that huge... She was obviously popular with the photographers because there were several pictures of her with her legs crossed in that album I went through in the newspapers.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh yeah?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: And remember you asked me who the two women were in that great big picture?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, the one with her legs crossed was his wife.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't remember asking you that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, you did.
[SPEAKER_00]: I showed it to you and I said, look at this.
[SPEAKER_00]: and that was his wife and you can tell a lot of those pictures that he has must be by professional photographers because they're all the same type i'll bet you tell about his picture collection oh it was fantastic and then he had he handed me an autograph book
[SPEAKER_00]: that I thought was an autograph book.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it was inscribed on the outside, the Chicago Cubs 1930.
[SPEAKER_02]: To Fred Blake, or Sheriff Blake.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, to Sheriff Blake.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I don't know right now how he got that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Do you suppose all of them would get it?
[SPEAKER_00]: Maybe they all got it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And there were pictures.
[SPEAKER_02]: Five by seven size pictures.
[SPEAKER_00]: Pictures of everybody on the team, all autographed.
Wow.
[SPEAKER_02]: Each one mounted on a separate page.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: And a neat little personal inscription on each one.
[SPEAKER_01]: Beautiful pictures, although one or two wrote across their face.
[SPEAKER_00]: I could have quite figured that out.
[SPEAKER_00]: But the, uh... You got a little flashlight?
[SPEAKER_02]: I can get your flashlight out so I can use it with my astray.
[SPEAKER_00]: and um he had all these uh he had scads and scads of pictures and you notice all the big pictures of him with the regular cardboard covers the white photographers used to give out formal portraits all had the cardinal emblem on them
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't know that many of them cardboard frames.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I guess I was the one that saw those, because I kept picking them up and putting them in envelopes, and he kept dumping them out.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he had the training schedule was printed for spring training.
[SPEAKER_00]: And at the end of spring training, they had a brochure with all the statistics on it of each player.
[SPEAKER_01]: He had the beautiful World Series programs of 1929 from each city.
[SPEAKER_01]: The Cubs program was small.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had the beautiful World Series programs of 1929 from each city.
[SPEAKER_00]: The Cubs program was small.
[SPEAKER_01]: and not very big, not very thick.
[SPEAKER_01]: Although it had some good pictures in it.
[SPEAKER_01]: The Philadelphia program was big, probably 9 by 12, much thicker with full length shots.
[SPEAKER_02]: The Cubs program just had the little head shots.
[SPEAKER_01]: Two beautiful World Series programs, with one of them, I think Chicago Cubs, one had the game scored.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the printed menu for the special train that they ran to Philadelphia from Chicago.
[SPEAKER_00]: And even on their training trips, on the trains they had printed menus, of which you now are the proud possessor of one.
[SPEAKER_00]: And what I was going to tell you was one was breakfast and one was dinner.
[SPEAKER_02]: They weren't the same then.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, they weren't the same.
[SPEAKER_00]: I started to tell you then I thought I wouldn't bother to say anything.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd just be quiet.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I'm sure he wouldn't have cared what he had taken when he's given away all his baseballs and everything.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I think his wife must have been awfully, an awfully kind-hearted woman.
[SPEAKER_00]: She seemed to mother everybody on the team.
[SPEAKER_02]: What was that story you told at the end there?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, after it came, he came out to get in the car.
[SPEAKER_00]: And there was a girl and a young man in it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And his wife said, I'm going to take them home.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the boy said something about the call on him.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he apparently had been sent in as a pinch hitter, I think.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so Blake realized he was on the other team.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was the first of a three-game series.
[SPEAKER_00]: Atlantis apparently didn't encourage this fraternization between the teams, from what I gather.
[SPEAKER_00]: But they took him home anyway.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the next day, the girl sat with Mrs. Blake in the stands because Mrs. Blake felt sorry for her.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she asked Mrs. Blake if Fred would get her an autographed ball for the club.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he did.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he sent it over to the clubhouse during the third game of the series.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he never saw the kid again.
[SPEAKER_00]: They never saw this young couple again.
[SPEAKER_00]: And later, this was in 1929, he got a letter
[SPEAKER_00]: from the commanding officer of the USS Concord, which is based in the east coast of Germany, thanking him for the autographed ball, which Phillips, apparently this boy's name was Phillips, had gotten from Blake, and how much it meant to the men on the ship, and they were all such great baseball fans,
[SPEAKER_00]: how they all wanted to handle it and they were smearing the autographs and some of them didn't believe it was real but this commander knew that it was and wishing him all the best and the team all the best in the coming year and if he was ever there in wherever the Concord was stationed or based to come and see him because they get a raw welcome.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was that story.
[SPEAKER_00]: What were some of those other stories?
[SPEAKER_01]: You mean this guy was actually on the Philadelphia team?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: He played on the team?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, his name was Phillips.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was Blake pitching against him when the call was pitched?
[SPEAKER_00]: I think so.
[SPEAKER_00]: Phillips was pitching.
[SPEAKER_02]: I found in the tape when I had to pursue that more fully.
[SPEAKER_02]: That was part of the story.
[SPEAKER_02]: And it was
[SPEAKER_01]: The commander was the kid's father?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, he was just a friend, apparently, or a nephew.
[SPEAKER_00]: This boy was a nephew of the commander.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he didn't think he had made it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because he never heard of him again.
He didn't.
[SPEAKER_00]: But then he told them stories afterwards.
[SPEAKER_00]: After the tape went off about baseball players.
[SPEAKER_02]: Will this place be open now?
[SPEAKER_02]: I would think they're open 24 hours a day.
[SPEAKER_02]: There's a snack bar a mile off the road from where I get a cup of coffee at.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't get run over by this truck first.
Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: I put out my blinker light to let him go.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's on him.
[SPEAKER_00]: And this is why I won't drive over Route 50 at night.
[SPEAKER_00]: It is.
[SPEAKER_00]: There, we're coming into it now.
You got your brake lights on?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, put them on so we can see how you get in.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's coming too.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is he right in here?
[SPEAKER_02]: The car's coming.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, we were on the right.
[SPEAKER_02]: Shut this thing down.
[SPEAKER_02]: Find where to shut it off at.
[SPEAKER_00]: Is it the lamp?
[SPEAKER_02]: Okay.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: What else did we have?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, there's a big bump here.
[SPEAKER_02]: Turn this way?
[SPEAKER_02]: Uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_01]: I just stopped for coffee at the Service Plaza 7 miles north of Princeton.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, it has a name.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm trying to get out of here.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'll tell you what the name is.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm trying to flashlight.
[SPEAKER_00]: it's called the uh bluestone stack park that guy's not gonna pull out right behind me is he coming
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, at least not for coffee, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd hate to be those women working in there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Like a what?
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, we have all that in the tape about, um, about her being a, didn't he say she was a, a nurse?
[SPEAKER_00]: Zayed or something?
[SPEAKER_00]: Or one?
[SPEAKER_00]: And he didn't marry her until 1925?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, and we're over what, he was 18.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: She may have been a little bit older than he was.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, that's what I'm thinking.
[SPEAKER_00]: Let me work it out that way.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, now, when was he, he played with the Cardinals in what year?
[SPEAKER_00]: I couldn't quite understand.
[SPEAKER_00]: He came up with the Pirates first.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, 1920.
[SPEAKER_01]: sold to the Cubs finally at 24 and at 31 he was he played with a couple of teams Cardinals I guess and then went back to the minor leagues and then came back up to the Browns in 1937-38 as far as we got him back up then
[SPEAKER_01]: And he said some story about, that's what I wanted to get on the tape, but didn't.
[SPEAKER_01]: A story about a ruin and bringing it back up at his age.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, OK, so that was it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And there was a big story in the paper about how Hornsby had called up this 38-year-old really pitcher, this 38-year-old pitcher there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he said he could help them go because he only wanted them
[SPEAKER_00]: It's a relief pitcher to fall back on.
[SPEAKER_00]: How long was he up?
[SPEAKER_00]: Two years?
[SPEAKER_02]: He may have been up part of 37, 38.
[SPEAKER_02]: Put your flashlight on.
I'm going to put the cigar out.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, I'd like to find it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And yeah, that was in there.
[SPEAKER_00]: When Farrell was traded, there was a great outburst in Chicago, apparently.
[SPEAKER_02]: Old Farrell.
[SPEAKER_00]: Old Farrell.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, they traded.
[SPEAKER_02]: That was on the tape, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_00]: I know, but there were several articles in there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Everybody was up in arms, apparently, in Chicago.
[SPEAKER_02]: They traded Old Farrell and George Grantham to the Cardinals for this young,
[SPEAKER_02]: Or Hartnett.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Gabby Hartnett.
[SPEAKER_02]: And O'Farrell became the most valuable player in the league that year at St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, I didn't know that.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, 1936, he was the most valuable player.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was there.
[SPEAKER_01]: He managed them.
[SPEAKER_01]: Coached them, or captained them.
[SPEAKER_02]: At any rate, Hartnett went on to have a much greater career than O'Farrell.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you interview Wormsby?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well...
[SPEAKER_01]: So there were a lot of stories in the book criticizing the trade.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, newspaper articles.
[SPEAKER_02]: Because the Cubs were mad at losing O'Farrell for this unheard of rookie heartening.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then there were the columns by Babe Ruth that he had written in some paper.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know which one.
[SPEAKER_02]: Christy Walsh wrote it probably.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because nothing was dated.
[SPEAKER_02]: None of the pictures have names on them either.
[SPEAKER_00]: in 1927 and 28 they had thermometers showing how ruse progress if he was going to better his own record so obviously they were keeping track of it but there was one article there it said something about gary went to columbia yeah eddie collins went to fordham now colin went to columbia too
[SPEAKER_02]: They both went to Columbia.
[SPEAKER_00]: Didn't Collins go to Florida?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_02]: Frisch went to Florida.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, Frisch went to Florida.
[SPEAKER_00]: Somebody named Mullins?
[SPEAKER_00]: Mullins?
[SPEAKER_00]: Said they all went to college.
[SPEAKER_00]: I did too.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went to the University of Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_02]: Mullins.
[SPEAKER_02]: Mullins, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: There was George Mullin who pitched for Detroit.
[SPEAKER_02]: But I think he was much earlier.
[SPEAKER_00]: I thought that was a name.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because they had Eddie Collins' picture in the paper.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they had a list of the players that had went to the different colleges.
[SPEAKER_00]: Obviously, none for very long.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't go to West Virginia Wesleyan very long.
Did he?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I couldn't quite understand that.
[SPEAKER_00]: I couldn't quite see how he ended up with Greenbrier Military Institute either.
[SPEAKER_02]: He went there first, I'm sure.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, he said he went there first.
[SPEAKER_01]: He went up to West Virginia Wesleyan.
[SPEAKER_01]: At least we found out that's how the Pirates heard about him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Pitching for West Virginia Wesleyan against some teams.
[SPEAKER_01]: Like Duquesne and them.
[SPEAKER_01]: Pirate connections.
[SPEAKER_01]: They heard about him.
[SPEAKER_01]: He must have done pretty well with WVW.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I would think that would be able to be checked out.
[SPEAKER_02]: Where?
[SPEAKER_00]: W-E-E-W. W-E-E-W. Did we get all that in the tape about his grandfather being a rebel?
[SPEAKER_02]: That may not be on the tape, because I think we were looking through some pictures, and I had it off about that.
[SPEAKER_01]: What was that story?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, his grandfather was in the Confederate Army.
[SPEAKER_00]: And after the war, he went, because he came from Virginia.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think maybe that is on the paper.
[SPEAKER_02]: Go ahead and tell it anyhow.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then he went to work in the mines, and he died of, I guess it would be black luck.
[SPEAKER_00]: In those days, they called it miner's asthma.
[SPEAKER_00]: When Fred Blake was five years old.
[SPEAKER_00]: His grandmother was just a little bitty woman of 90.
[SPEAKER_00]: She was always waiting for a pension.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: But his wife must have been something the way she drove the whole boat even for us in country in those days.
[SPEAKER_02]: A very self-reliant woman.
[SPEAKER_02]: As you say, she probably helped him a lot.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, I'm sure she must have.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because that picture in the beach, he was the one in shorts.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, that was some picture.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
Yeah, she was a very striking woman.
There was an article in there about English.
[SPEAKER_00]: He must just have come up.
[SPEAKER_00]: And now he had...
[SPEAKER_00]: struck out five times or something in a row that was one little story and then of course the story's in there about the headline i showed you about jess haynes